ko-fi.com 2019-12-31

# Privacy

## **Privacy Policy and Cookie Policy for Ko-fi.com**  

####  **Updated 24th August 2018**  

###  **1.Introduction**

This is our privacy policy. It tells you how we collect and process data received from you on our site [www.ko-fi.com](http://www.ko-fi.com/) \- Please read the following carefully to understand our views and practices regarding your personal data and how we will treat it. If you have any comments on this privacy policy, please email them to [**data@ko-fi.com**](mailto:data@ko-fi.com) **.**

Ko-fi is not a payment processor, Ko-fi facilitates payments directly between users of the platform via third party payment providers such as PayPal and Stripe. Before creating an account or making a payment please take a moment to read the privacy policies of these payment providers.

  * <https://www.paypal.com/en/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full>
  * <https://stripe.com/gb/privacy>

###  **2.Who We Are**

  * Our site address is **www.ko-fi.com**
  * Our company name is **Ko-fi Labs Limited**
  * Our company number is **11087704**
  * Our registered address is **The Station House, 15 Station Road, St Ives PE27 5BH**
  * Our nominated representative is **Simon Ellington** and they can be contacted at [**data@ko-fi.com**](mailto:data@ko-fi.com)

###  **3.What we may collect**

We may collect and process the following data about you:

  * Contact information such as name and email address either entered directly or transmitted via a social sign up facility such as ‘sign up with Google’ or ‘sign up with Facebook’,
  * Information you put into forms or surveys on our site,
  * Information you put into your Ko-fi profile and updates to your profile including but not limited to images, hashtags, text updates and links to third party websites or content,
  * Information you enter to send or receive payments such as PayPal email address or Stripe Connected Account information,
  * Details of transactions you carry out through our site,
  * Details of your visits to our site and the resources you use,
  * Information about your computer (e.g. your IP address, browser, operating system, etc.) for system administration and to report aggregate information to our advertisers,
  * The referring url (where a visitor to a page came from).
  * Marketing preferences information which can be managed at [notification settings](https://ko-fi.com/Manage/notifications),
  * Other personal information you choose to disclose to us for any reason.

Under GDPR we will ensure that your personal data is processed lawfully, fairly, and transparently, without adversely affecting your rights. We collect and process your personal data;

  * As necessary to fulfill our [Terms and Conditions of Use](https://ko-fi.com/Home/Terms)
  * Consistent with your consent which you may revoke at any time through the [deletion of your account](https://ko-fi.com/Manage/DeleteAccount)
  * As is necessary for the performance of a contract to which you are a party
  * As necessary to comply with our legal obligations
  * To protect your vital interest or those of others
  * As necessary in the public interest
  * For our legitimate interest in the provision of a service to our users and partners unless those interests may be overridden by your interests or fundamental rights and freedoms that require the protection of personal data.   

> **In a Nutshell**   
> In order to provide the service to you, we collect some personal information from you and your device. 

‍

###  **4.Cookies**

All Cookies used by and on our website are used in accordance with current English and EU Cookie Law. The site uses cookies to collect information about your access to the site. Cookies are pieces of information that include a unique reference code that a website transfers to your device to store and sometimes track information about you. Some of the cookies we use last only for the duration of your web session and expire when you close your browser. Other cookies are used to remember you when you return to the site and will last for longer.

 **Disabling Cookies**

Most computer and some mobile web browsers automatically accept cookies but, if you prefer, you can change your browser to prevent that or to notify you each time a cookie is set. You can prevent the setting of cookies by adjusting the settings on your browser. If you do disable cookies it may not be possible to use the service.  

 **Our cookies will be used for:**

Essential session management

  * creating a specific log-in session for a user of the site in order that the site remembers that a user is logged in and that their page requests are delivered in an effective, secure and consistent manner;
  * recognising when a user of the site has visited before allowing us to identify the number of unique users we receive to the site and make sure we have enough capacity for the number of users that we get;
  * recognising if a visitor to the site is registered with us in any way;
  * we may also log information including the existence of cookies, your IP address and information about your browser program in order to allow us to diagnose problems, administer and monitor overall usage of our site.

 **Functionality**

  * customising elements of the content of the pages of the site.

 **Performance and measurement**

  * collecting statistical information about how our users use the site so that we can improve the site and learn which parts are most popular to users.

>  **In a Nutshell**   
> Ko-fi.com use cookies to operate the service and improve it.

‍

###  **5.How we use what we collect**

We use information about you to:

  * Present site content effectively,
  * Provide information about the service and connected supporters or creators pages of which may be of interest,
  * Tell you about additional services available to you,
  * Carry out our contracts with you,
  * Allow you to use our interactive services if you want to,
  * Comply with the acceptable use policies of payment partners such as PayPal and Stripe,
  * Tell you our charges for premium, gold or pro services where appropriate

If you don't want to be contacted for marketing purposes, please adjust your [notification settings](https://ko-fi.com/Manage/notifications) in your dashboard. 

Please note: We don't identify individuals to our advertisers, but we may give them aggregate information to help them reach their target audience, and we may use information we have collected to display advertisements to that audience.

In addition, if you don’t want us to use your personal data for any of the other reasons set out in this section in 5, you can let us know at any time by contacting us at [data@ko-fi.com](mailto:data@ko-fi.com), and we will delete your data from our systems. However, you acknowledge this will remove our ability to provide the service to you.

>  **In a Nutshell**   
> We use the data we collect to provide the service to you and occasionally we may show relevant advertising 

‍

###  **6.Where we store your data**

We may transfer your collected data to storage outside the European Economic Area (EEA). It may be processed outside the EEA to provide the service to you.

By giving us your personal data, you agree to this arrangement. We will do what we reasonably can to keep your data secure.

If we give you a password, you must keep it confidential. Please don't share it. Although we try to provide protection, we cannot guarantee complete security for your data, and you take the risk that any sending of that data turns out to be not secure despite our efforts.

We only keep your personal data for as long as we need to in order to use it as described above in section 5, and/or for as long as we have your permission to keep it. In any event, we will conduct an annual review to ascertain whether we need to keep your personal data. Your personal data will be deleted automatically if we no longer need it.

>  **In a Nutshell**   
> Your data is stored securely, and we don’t keep it for longer than we need it. Your data is transferred to some suppliers located outside of the EEA.

‍

###  **7.Disclosing your information**

We are allowed to disclose your information in the following cases:

  * If we want to sell the service or the company, we can disclose it to the potential buyer.
  * We can disclose it to other businesses in our group.
  * We can disclose it if we have a legal obligation to do so, or in order to protect other people's property, safety or rights.
  * If a payment provider such as PayPal or Stripe requests access to it.
  * We can exchange information with others to protect against fraud or credit risks.

We may contract with third parties to supply services to you on our behalf. These may include payment processing, search engine facilities, advertising and marketing. In some cases, the third parties may require access to some or all of your data. Where any of your data is required for such a purpose, we will take all reasonable steps to ensure that your data will be handled safely, securely, and in accordance with your rights, our obligations, and the obligations of the third party under GDPR and the law.

>  **In a Nutshell**   
> Reputable third-party suppliers and partners are used to process personal data. We may transfer your personal data to these suppliers.  

‍

###  **8.Your rights**

You can ask us not to use your data for marketing. You can do this by updating your [notification settings](https://ko-fi.com/Manage/notifications) or by contacting us at any time at [data@ko-fi.com](mailto:data@ko-fi.com)

Under the GDPR, you have the right to:

  * request access to, deletion of or correction of, your personal data held by us at no cost to you; 
  * be informed of what data processing is taking place;
  * restrict processing;
  * to object to processing of your personal data; and
  * complain to a supervisory authority.

To enforce any of the foregoing rights or if you have any other questions about our site or this Privacy Policy, please contact us at [data@ko-fi.com](mailto:data@ko-fi.com).

>  **In a Nutshell**   
> You can opt out of receiving marketing in your notification preferences or ask us anything about the data we hold about you.

‍

###  **9.Links to other sites**

Please note that our [Terms of Use](https://ko-fi.com/home/terms) and our policies will not apply to other websites that you get to via a link from our site. We have no control over how your data is collected, stored or used by other websites and we advise you to check the privacy policies of any such websites before providing any data to them.

>  **In a Nutshell**   
> We are not responsible for any other sites not operated by Ko-fi Labs Limited

‍

###  **10.Changes**

If we change our Privacy Policy, we will post the changes on this page. If we decide to, we may also email you.

>  **In a Nutshell**   
> Come back to this page for updates

‍
